Eduardo Godoy

Software Architect | Informatics Enginieer

□ +56 9 89573321 @ eduardo.gl@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/godoyeduardo ♀ github.com/EdGoll

i DNI: 15.557.610-3 i chilean i Born date: February 4, 1983, 37 years old. 💡 Jorge Kenrick #989-55, Valparaíso, Chile.



Summary

Computer Engineer with extensive experience in the development of business applications using Java JEE technology and design and implementation of architectures. Currently I have the role of Senior Software Architect, I also do teaching work allowing to deliver my knowledge and experiences to future professionals. I consider myself a person who watches over good relationships personal, trained to deliver knowledge, proactive and always available to support my colleagues.



Work Experience

2016 - 2020 Sr. Software Architect., Nationals Customs Service, Government of Chile.

- > Design and implementation of rest APIs as part of an event-driven architecture.
- > Design and Implementation of building blocks as reusable pieces of software to compose designs and software implementation.
- > Definition of strategy for an efficient migration of applications to the cloud.
- > Design of architectures for the development of projects of the government of Chile.
- > Definition of architectural guidelines and verification of correct implementation within software development projects
- > Design and implementation of integration projects .
- > Implementation of archetypes of applications, services and processes for agile development.
- > Training and continuous help to developers in knowledge of technology and resolution of coding problems.
- > Portfolio management of architecture projects.

Java | JBoss EAP | Apache Camel | Spring framework | Jenkins | git | Angular 7 | Bootstraps | REST | Camel containers OpenShift microservices

2012 - 2016

Software Architect, Emergya, Consulting.

- > Design and implementation of archetype for software development.
- > Implementation of component architectures.
- > JBoss ESB-based Components Implementation.
- > Research and adoption of new technologies for continuous improvement of development processes.
- > Technical support to areas of development and operations in projects and contingencies.
- > Definition of architectural guidelines and standards for project and component development.
- > Execution of code audits for projects in development stage.

JBoss EAP JBoss SOA-P JSF RichFaces Eclipse IDE Hibernate Alfresco

2010 - 2012 Software engineer, Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile.

- > Technical leader of projects in the area of education, using Java J2EE technology with ICEfaces and EJB frameworks.
- > Design and implementation of high availability production environment.
- > Design and implementation of student portal.
- > Design and implementation of base architecture for new development projects.
- > Design and implementation of base architecture for new development projects.

Glassfish Ms Sql Server Java iceFaces MyBatis

2009 - 2010 Software engineer Java, Tecnova, Chile

- > Project development for Java and Php telecommunications industry.
- > Evolutionary maintenance project for a life insurance company operations platform.
- > Geolocation project to record bandwidth measurements of BAM plans.
- > Development of measurement query application for help desk platform.
- > Design and implementation of a web application to record the activities of insurance agents using

Eclipse Java JSP JSF ADFfaces Oracle Php Jquery Visual Basic

2008 - 2009

Data integration consultant, Power Data, Chile

- > Implementation of ETL processes in the Retail industry client.
- > Design and implementation of ETL process for mapping transactions from Cobol to relational data-

PowerCenter Cobol DB2 TeraData

January 2008 July 2008

Developer, DyBox, Chile

> Support for Java JEE application development.

ADFfaces EJB 2.1 TopLink OC4J.



Teaching

2017-2019

Universidad de Valparaíso, Faculty of Engineering,

- > Programming II Java.
- > Design Methodology.
- > Programming languages.

2010 - 2014

Universidad de Viña del Mar, School of Technology,

- > Analysis and design methodology.
- > Programming languages I.
- > Programming languages I.
- > Web development I.
- > Web development II.
- > Advanced Topics in Software Development.
- > Artificial intelligence.
- > Title seminar I.
- > Title seminar II.



Education

- 2020 Phd Candidate (in progress), Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile
- 2009 Informatics Engineer, Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile
- 2009 Degree in Computer Science, Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile

Competencies

Java, Php, C, python, Angular, .Net-Core, ETEX. Programming languages:

> Frameworks: JSF (Primefaces, RichFaces, iceFaces), Spring Framework, camel, Javascript (¡Query, Angu-

> > lar, Bootstrap), Hibernate, MyBatis

Data Base: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Ms SQL Server

Development Tools: Eclipse, NetBeans, IntelliJ Idea, Maven, Ant, git, SVN

Middleware: JBoss EAP, JBoss SOA-P, Fuse, Tomcat, Glassfish

Sistemas Operativos: Windows, Windows 2003 Server, Linux (Redhat, Centos, Ubuntu), FreBSD.

Software design tools: UML, Archi, Enterprise Architect.

Machine learning tools: python sklearn, Keras, tensor flow, Textblob.

Tools and Technologies Jenkins, Sonar, Jmeter, Talend, Power Center, Dockers, AWS, OpenShift

> Others: Clean code, Refactoring and Design and Enterprise Intergration Patterns.

Training courses

- 2020 Application Development II: Implementing Microservice Architectures (DO283). Red Hat
- 2020 Application Development I: Programming in Java EE (AD183). Red Hat
- 2020 Introduction to Openshift Applications I (DO101). Red Hat
- 2018 Jboss Fuse camel (JB421). Red Hat
- 2018 Jboss Enterprise Application Development (JB225). Red Hat
- 2017 Jboss Enterprise Application Development II (JB325). Red Hat
- 2016 Jboss Development with Hibernate Technology (JB297). Red Hat
- 2016 Jboss Enterprise Application Development (JB225). Red Hat
- 2015 Collaborative skills for the change (couching). LW Capacitaciones
- 2014 ITIL v3 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management. Axelos

Certifications.

- 2014 ITIL v3 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management. EXIN, ID 5158119.20318946
- 2018 **Analyst developer of software applications (TIC-PROG)** . ISFIA, ID a02785f4-7a11-4f20-9f29-890b52299a08

Languages



References

Guillermo Farias, Manager of Departament of services IT

- National customs services.
 - **1** +56 9 84492402
- @ gfarias@aduana.cl

Cristian Villatoro, CEO

- i datamapit.
 - **1** +56 9 95162719
- @ cristian.villatoro@datamapit.cl